Roy Chancellor

Java programmer and tenacious problem solver seeking developer position

Passionate and tenacious problem solver with over 20 years of experience in engineering and education with advanced skills in technical problem solving, process mapping, and product development life cycle pursuing a career in Java programming. Self-motivated to exceed customer expectations whenever possible. Clear communicator who can convey technical information accurately and simply to all audience levels.

Experience

2019 Java Programming

- 16 credit-hours of coursework in Java object-oriented programming
- Developed Java banking application with object-oriented class structures using Maven framework In Eclipse IDE
- Key skills: Java, Spring Boot, REST, AWS, Maven, Git
- Completed online course in JavaScript and built a ### application with ### technologies
- Completed online Python course and built a ### application with ### libraries

2015 Engineering

1993 - 2006 and 2013 - 2015

15 years experience in problem-solving and leadership roles. Problem Solving

- Solved a chronic problem of connector latches interfering with ribbon cables in relay assemblies that prevented a line shutdown
- Created a unique stiffener that solved shock-induced PCB cracking that enabled flight qualification on schedule
- Wrote a program that dialed a pager to alert operators when a constraint machine went down that created precious hours of production
- Co-led a team that minimized brightness variation for automotive EL lamps leave to zero customer complaints

Six Sigma Master Black Belt

- Led a corporate-level team of black belts that completed projects across the company netting > \$1M savings over 3 years
- Solved numerous quality problems before, during, and after product launches that led to increased yield and happier customers

Modem Test Programmer

 Automated final testing of satellite modems by writing and deploying C programs that reduced testing time by >50%

Employment History

- Manufacturing Engineer, Schweitzer Engineering Laboratory (2013 2015)
- Statistician, Intel Corporation (2005 2006)
- Six Sigma Master Black Belt, Rogers Corporation (1999 2005)
- **Mechanical Engineer**, Orbital Sciences Corporation (1998 1999)
- Process Engineer, W.L. Gore and Associates (1994 1998)
- Automated Test Programmer, EF Data (1993 1994)

2006 Mathematics Educator

2006 - 2013 and 2015 - 2019

11 years experience as a mathematics teacher recognized for extreme organization, clarity, and passion.

Organization, Leadership, and Communication

- Created open-source curricula spanning Algebra 1 through Calculus 2 that saved new teachers countless hours of preparation
- Designed the school master schedule by solving dozens of logic conflicts and wrote unit-test code in Excel VBA to identify conflicts before deployment

Personal Info

Address

2014 East Anderson Drive Phoenix, Arizona 85022

Phone

480.242.6356

E-mail

roychance600@gmail.com

WWW

roychancellor.me

GitHub

github.com/roychancellor

LinkedIn

linkedin.com/in/roychancellor

Skills

Java language: Skilled at writing objectoriented code that is clean and easy to maintain with a focus on understanding the language, not just frameworks



Front-end web design: Able to use **HTML** and **CSS** to create static web pages; basic proficiency in **JavaScript** to create dynamic sites.



C/C++: Wrote code to acquire & display data from A/D cards, communicate through RS-232, simulate dynamic systems, and perform mathematical computations



Python: Basic skills acquired through online course



VBA: Wrote VBA code to automate data processes in Excel



Data analysis: Skilled at JMP and Minitab to analyze complex data sets across a variety of disciplines



Courses

Java Programming I, II, and III

Open Source Computing

C Programming

Regression Analysis I and II

Design of Experiments I and II

Theory of Statistics I and II

Introduction to Numerical Methods

- Organized and led student trips to Washington D.C., including budgeting, solving logistics problems, and communicating with students and families
- Mentored math teachers with formal and informal observations, including one who became a master teacher

Employment History

- Master Teacher of Mathematics , Great Hearts Academies (2010 2013 and 2015 2019)
- Mathematics Teacher, Great Hearts Academies (2008 2010)
- Mathematics Teacher, Scottsdale Unified School District (2006 2008)

Education

2019 Certificate in Java Programming, Grand Canyon University

- 16-credit hours of core Java language and object-oriented principles
- Frameworks and tools include Eclipse, Maven, Spring, AWS, REST, HTML, CSS, React
- **2004 Graduate Certificate in Applied Statistics**, Rochester Institute of Technology
- **M.S. Mechanical Engineering**, Texas A&M University
 - **Thesis**: Parameter Identification Using Nonlinear Dynamics and Chaos (article published in the ASME Journal of Vibration and Acoustics, July 1996)
 - Co-created a micro controller-based active-damping system for a 1/4 car suspension by writing C code that implemented PID control
 - Simulated the dynamic response of a five-pendulum test rig using C language code to solve the matrix equations of motion
- **1991** B.S.E. Mechanical Engineering, Arizona State University